Sina Sajadmanesh Last update: 05 Jul, 2021

CONTACT INFORMATION Rue Marconi 19 1920 Martigny Switzerland (+41) 27-721-77-58 ****sajadmanesh@idiap.ch

https://sajadmanesh.com

♣

RESEARCH SUMMARY My research interests lie at the intersection of privacy, deep learning, and graph analysis. More specifically, I use privacy enhancing technologies, such as differential privacy and federated learning, with graph representation learning algorithms, including graph neural networks, to make them more private, secure, and robust for real-world applications.

EDUCATION

École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL), Lausanne, Switzerland, May 2019 – May 2023

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering GPA: 5.7 / 6

Thesis: Learning over Graphs: A Privacy-Preserving Approach

Adviser: Prof. Daniel Gatica-Perez

Relevant Courses: Artificial Neural Networks (Deep Reinforcement Learning), Deep Learning for Natural Language Processing, Advanced Topics in Machine Learning

Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran, Sep 2014 – Sep 2016

M.Sc. in Information Technology Engineering GPA: 18.1 / 20

Thesis: Link Prediction in Heterogeneous Multi-Layer Social Networks

Adviser: Prof. Hamid R. Rabiee

Relevant Courses: Machine Learning, Complex Dynamical Networks, Performance Modeling of Computer Systems, Advanced Network Security, Database Security and Privacy

University of Isfahan, Esfahan, Iran, Sep 2009 – Feb 2014

B.Sc. in Computer Software Engineering GPA: 16.19 / 20 (Last four semesters: 17.4 / 20)

Project: Design and Implementation of an Android App for Voice Control of Household Devices

Adviser: Prof. Ahamd R. Naghsh-Nilchi

Relevant Courses: Data Structures, Algorithms, Probability and Statistics, Artificial Intelligence, Information Retrieval, Software Engineering, Databases, Operating Systems, Computer Networks

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant, May 2019 – present

Social Computing Group, Idiap Research Institute, Martigny, Switzerland

• Developing privacy-preserving graph neural network models using differential privacy to reduce the privacy risks of using graph representation learning algorithms in real applications.

Research Assistant, (Offered, but declined due to visa problems)

IBM-ILLINOIS Center for Cognitive Computing Systems Research, **University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign**, Champaign, Illinois, United States

Research Assistant, Nov 2014 - May 2019

Data Science and Machine Learning Lab, Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

- Privacy-Preserving Deep Learning: Worked on a hybrid approach based on Siamese fine-tuning and split learning to make non-private pre-trained deep learning models privacy-preserving at the inference stage.
- Web Data Science: Analyzed a large-scale collection of recipes published on the web and their content, aiming to understand cuisines and culinary habits around the world.
- <u>Social and Information Networks:</u> Developed time-aware link prediction algorithms over heterogeneous social networks using recurrent neural networks and non-parametric machine learning.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Guest Lecturer, Fall 2017

Department of Computer Engineering, Sharif University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

Course: Fundamentals of Programming (Python) **Website:** http://ce.sharif.edu/courses/96-97/1/ce153-12/

Teaching Assistant

EPFL

• Computational Social Media (Head TA), Spring 2021

Sharif University of Technology

- Artificial Intelligence (Head TA), Spring 2017
- Advanced Topics in Artificial Intelligence Statistical Learning Theory, Spring 2016
- Engineering Probability and Statistics, Spring 2016

University of Isfahan

- Artificial Intelligence, Fall 2013
- Advanced Computer Programming 2 JavaFx and Android, Fall 2012

Sina Sajadmanesh Last update: 05 Jul, 2021

- Computer Programming Java, Fall 2011
- Computer Programming C++, Fall 2010

INDUSTRIAL EXPERIENCE

Big-Data Engineer, Sep 2018 – May 2019

Sharif ICT Innovation Center, Tehran, Iran

• Responsible for building a native big-data processing platform using state-of-the-art technologies, such as Spark, Cassandra, JanusGraph, Elasticsearch, etc.

Software Engineering Intern, Summer 2012

Amin Computer Co., Esfahan, Iran

Responsible for designing and developing an Android application for company's web-based human resource management system.

PUBLICATIONS

[1] Sina Sajadmanesh and Daniel Gatica-Perez

Locally Private Graph Neural Networks

ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS 2021), Nov 2021

[2] Seyed Ali Osia, Ali Shahin Shamsabadi, Sina Sajadmanesh, et al. A Hybrid Deep Learning Architecture for Privacy-Preserving Mobile Analytics IEEE Internet of Things Journal, May 2020

[3] Sina Sajadmanesh, Sogol Bazargani, Jiawei Zhang, and Hamid R. Rabiee Continuous-Time Relationship Prediction in Dynamic Heterogeneous Information Networks ACM Transactions on Knowledge Discovery from Data, Aug 2019

[4] Sina Sajadmanesh, Jiawei Zhang, and Hamid R. Rabiee NPGLM: A Non-Parametric Method for Temporal Link Prediction

Technical Report, ArXiv e-prints, Jun 2017

[5] Sina Sajadmanesh, Sina Jafarzadeh, Seyed Ali Ossia, et al. Kissing Cuisines: Exploring Worldwide Culinary Habits on the Web International World Wide Web Conference (WWW 2017) Companion, Apr 2017

[6] Sina Sajadmanesh, Hamid R. Rabiee and Ali Khodadadi Predicting Anchor Links between Heterogeneous Social Networks IEEE/ACM International Conference on Advances in Social Networks Analysis and Mining, Aug 2016

Media Coverage

- MIT Technology Review, How Data Mining Reveals the World's Healthiest Cuisines, 3 Nov 2016
- The Independent, These are the world's most diverse cuisines, 11 Nov 2016
- France 24, Un algorithme compare les cuisines du monde en matière d'ingrédients et d'apports nutritionnels,
 15 Nov 2016
- Sciences et Avenir, Les cuisines du monde passées au crible des big data, 14 Nov 2016

TALKS AND

Locally Private Graph Neural Networks, Jun 2021

PRESENTATIONS

AI4Media Workshop on Explainability, Robustness and Privacy in AI, Remote

Locally Private Graph Neural Networks, Jan 2021

Twitter Machine Learning Seminar, Remote

Privacy-Preserving Deep Learning Over Graphs, Dec 2020

Information Processing and Communications Lab, Imperial College London, Remote

PROFESSIONAL

SERVICES

- Reviewer: IEEE Transactions on Big Data (2021)
- Reviewer: Distributed and Private Machine Learning Workshop (2021)
- Reviewer: ACM Transactions on Intelligent Systems and Technology (2020)
- Reviewer: Social Network Analysis and Mining Journal (2020)
- Reviewer: World Wide Web Journal (2018)

HONORS AND AWARDS

- PhD admission, Computer Science, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, 2018 (declined)
- PhD admission Computer Science, Hong-Kong University of Science and Technology, 2017 (declined)
- Ranked 3rd in cumulative GPA among B.Sc. Computer Software Engineering students admitted for Fall 2009, University of Isfahan, 2014

Sina Sajadmanesh Last update: 05 Jul, 2021

• Ranked 6th in Iranian nationwide university entrance exam for graduate studies, field of Artificial Intelligence, among more than 100000 students, 2014

- Ranked 15th in Iranian nationwide university entrance exam for graduate studies, field of Computer Networks and Security, among more than 30000 students, 2014
- Ranked 28th in 18th National Computer Olympiad for University Students at Tarbiat Modares University, Tehran, Iran, 2013
- Ranked 16th in ACM-ICPC regional contest, Asia region, Tehran site, among more than 70 teams at University of Tehran, Tehran, Iran, 2011
- Ranked 2nd in nationwide collegiate programming contest among more than 70 teams at University of Kashan, Kashan, Iran, 2010
- Ranked among top 0.02% in Iran's nationwide university entrance exam for undergraduate studies., 2009

MEMBERSHIPS ACM Professional Member, 2020 – Present

ACM Student Member, 2011 - 2014

ACM-ICPC Student Chapter, University of Isfahan, Esfahan, Iran, 2010 – 2012

TECHNICAL Programming:

SKILLS Python, Java, C, C++, MATLAB, PHP, Javascript

Information Retrieval & Analytics: Elasticsearch, JanusGraph, Cassandra

Data Science and Machine Learning:

PyTorch, PyTorch-Geometric, PyTorch-Lightning, Scikit-Learn, Pandas

REFERENCES **Prof. Daniel Gatica-Perez**, Idiap Research Institute, EPFL

Prof. Hamid R. Rabiee, Department of Computer Engineering, Sharif University of Technology

Prof. Hamed Haddadi, Dyson School of Design Engineering, Imperial College London Website: https://haddadi.github.io/ Email: h.haddadi@imperial.ac.uk

Prof. Emiliano De Cristofaro, Department of Computer Science, University College London

Website: https://emilianodc.com/ Email: e.decristofaro@ucl.ac.uk